<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-06-12T17:11:20+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Your awesome title</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Jekyll!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2017/06/12/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Jekyll!" /><published>2017-06-12T17:01:05+02:00</published><updated>2017-06-12T17:01:05+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2017/06/12/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2017/06/12/welcome-to-jekyll.html">&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Tom'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Investing in businesses and products</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/user/experiences/2017/06/12/investing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Investing in businesses and products" /><published>2017-06-12T17:01:05+02:00</published><updated>2017-06-12T17:01:05+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/user/experiences/2017/06/12/investing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/user/experiences/2017/06/12/investing.html">&lt;p&gt;For the past decade, I’ve been getting more and more into stock trading and (long term) investing. Last year, I got the opportunity to invest in Hyper Island, even though most of my investments are in publicly traded companies like Apple, Netflix or Square.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have developed a couple of simple rules I like to follow (although I sometimes fail at this!). The rules might seem extremely naive but you’d be amazed at the valuations some of the companies have that fail to fulfil all of the criteria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The company sells a product I understand. 
  There are countless of occasions where I’ve been intrigued by a rumour or a “common perception” that a company is about to sky rocket only to realise it didn’t happen for reasons I couldn’t predict, nor understand. Now, even the tech industry have areas that I don’t understand - and certainly can’t predict - but at least I have a fairly good understanding of what makes a good tech product. Biotech, medicare or retail - I have little to none understanding of how it works so it makes sense for me to stay out of those industries. Investing in what you don’t understand is not that different than playing the lottery.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The company sells a product I like.
  There are products I understand (like Facebook) but that I can’t say I particularly like. To be honest, I’ve been thinking of leaving Facebook all together because I’m not a fan of the product. So should I really invest in products I don’t like, regardless of what the financial upside might be?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The company has a (viable) business model.
  This might seem like a no-brainer, and tech stocks aside, there aren’t that many companies listed that doesn’t have a viable business model. But companies like Twitter have struggled for years in finding a business model that’s viable. Part of the problem here is that valuations for services companies is heavily tied to KPIs like MAU (Monthly Active Users) and MNU (Monthly New Users) rather than economics. Other companies, take Uber for instance, might have a business model but one that is heavily dependent on them finding loop holes in local law regulations. It’s not viable in the long term.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While these three simple rules might seem so basic, you’d be amazed at how hard it is to find companies that can check off all three requirements. Because of the last days downfall, I’ve sold off most of my tech investments but when I’m getting back in, I might stick to two-three of my favourites; AAPL and NFLX (perhaps SHOP too). I’d love to see Stripe and Mailchimp go public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What about your product/company? Hopefully you’re loving it but is it a product that most people understand? Can you explain your product to me in 30 seconds or less? Even the most basic apps fail at this because they want to explain everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in investing, check out Samwise from Lisa and Dan. Love new fintech-startups like these.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">For the past decade, I’ve been getting more and more into stock trading and (long term) investing. Last year, I got the opportunity to invest in Hyper Island, even though most of my investments are in publicly traded companies like Apple, Netflix or Square.</summary></entry></feed>